A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Rockefeller Boards, Series O FA324
Rockefeller Archive Center
- China Medical Board
  - China Medical Board - Oriental Trip - Letters to Chinese, 1921-1923 (Box 15, Folder 138)
    Letter of thanks to Chinese from John D. Rockefeller, Jr.; list of Chinese officials.
  - China Medical Board - Oriental Trip - Newspapers, 1921-1922 (Box 15, Folder 139)
    Clippings on trip; requests for articles; interviews held on John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s opinions. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - China Medical Board - Peking Union Medical College - Map of Campus, 1921 (Box 15, Folder 140)
    Photo of blueprint of buildings given to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. in China, August 1921. Item separated to map collection.
    Separated Materials note
    Item housed with the map collection.
  - Copy of Blueprints from PUMC (China Medical Board Architectural Department), 1921 August 9; ARCHITECTURAL DRAWING (Quantity 1) (Drawer B 1, Folder 91)
  - China Medical Board - China Trip - Edmund R. Willets, 1921 (Box 15, Folder 140A)
    A 30-minute audio cassette tape of Colonel William Howard's recollections of Edmund R. Willets's 1921 trip to China in the John D. Rockefeller, Jr. party has been separated to the audio-visual collection. This folder also contains a brief biographical sketch of Edmund R. Willets and his wife Virginia Lippold Willets, and a copy of an index to Howard's interview.
    The audio cassette tape has been separated to the audio-visual collection, along with an index to the interview.
  - China Medical Board - Peking Union Medical College - Map of Campus, August 1921 (Box F 091, Folder 6)
    Photo of blueprint of buildings at Peking Union Medical College, produced by the China Medical Board Architecture Department, August 9, 1921. Given to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. in China, August 1921.
- Davison Fund
  - Davison Fund, Inc., 1934-1960 (Box 15, Folder 141)
    Organization of Fund; legal fees; approval of minutes; elections. Packard's health; finances; loan to Fund from John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Thomas M. Debevoise, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Robert W. Gumbel, C. M. Belknap, Lefferts M. Dashiell.
  - Davison Fund, Inc. - By-Laws, Certificate of Incorporation, 1934-1938 (Box 15, Folder 142)
    Charter, by-laws, revisions, certificate of incorporation.
  - Davison Fund, Inc. - Letter of Gift, October 17, 1934, 1934-1940 (Box 15, Folder 143)
    Delivery of stock and money, 1934; rejected pledge, 1937; John D. Rockefeller 3rd's 1939 gift.
  - Davison Fund, Inc. - Exemption from Taxation, 1934-1937 (Box 15, Folder 144)
- General Education Board
  - General Education Board - Organization, Charter, By-Laws, 1902-1950 (Box 15, Folder 145)
    Organization of Board; act creating Board; temporary association; incorporation. Correspondents include Frederick T. Gates, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - General Education Board - Correspondence about Charter, 1902 (Box 15, Folder 146)
    Passage of bill creating General Education Board.
  - General Education Board - 1899 Correspondence about Future Education Fund, 1899-1901 (Box 15, Folder 147)
    Question of legality; relation to Southern Education Board.
  - General Education Board - Relations with Department of Agriculture, 1914-1919 (Box 15, Folder 148)
    Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Albert Shaw.
  - General Education Board - Memoranda, 1905 (Box 15, Folder 149)
    Secretaries' tentative program of preliminary work, 1905; later reports. Correspondents include Starr J. Murphy, Wallace Buttrick.
  - General Education Board - Nominating Committee, 1947-1961 (Box 16, Folder 150)
    Selection of committee; nominations for Board and committee. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, William I. Myers, Edward Lee Norton, Robert D. Calkins, Harvie Branscomb.
    32.3
    General note
    Open per CLS, 01/22/2008.
  - General Education Board - Elections and Resignations, 1909-1956 (Box 16, Folder 151)
    Search for persons to fill vacancies; elections. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Wallace Buttrick, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, W. H. Page, Albert Shaw, W. W. Brierley, Lefferts M. Dashiell, Jerome D. Greene, Harry Pratt Judson, Wickliffe Rose, Eben C. Sage, George E. Vincent.
  - General Education Board - Elections and Resignations - John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s Letters, 1912-1937 (Box 16, Folder 152)
    Resignations of Frederick T. Gates, Trevor Arnett, and Mr. Shaw, and Dr. H. W. Chase.
  - General Education Board - John D. Rockefeller 3rd Membership, 1931-1961 (Box 16, Folder 153)
  - General Education Board - Meetings, 1935-1959 (Box 16, Folder 154)
    Summaries of minutes of Board.
  - General Education Board - John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s Retirement, 1939 (Box 16, Folder 155)
    Transmission of John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s remarks at April 6, 1939 meeting; comments on them. Correspondents include Thomas M. Debevoise, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Raymond B. Fosdick.
  - General Education Board - John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s Retirement, 1939 (Box 16, Folder 156)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s remarks at April 6, 1939 meeting; copy of remarks as read and as edited for publication; published copy.
  - General Education Board - General, 1902-1911 (Box 16, Folder 157)
    Grants to Iowa colleges; report on Southern Education Board; studies; policy decisions; reports; activities of Board members; question of whether grant should be made to Oriental Institute. Political quarrel over Dr. Sanchez's activities in New Mexico; disposition of Spelman estate - bequest to General Education Board; administration of bequests and gifts; changes in officers and personnel. Legal status of General Education Board; crank and crackpot letters; tributes, memorials; dissolution. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Wallace Buttrick, Starr J. Murphy, Frederick T. Gates, Louis G. Myers, George Foster Peabody, Robert C. Ogden, Eben C. Sage, Charles W. Eliot.
    32.4
  - General Education Board - General, 1912-1921 (Box 16, Folder 158)
    Grants to Iowa colleges; report on Southern Education Board; studies; policy decisions; reports; activities of Board members; question of whether grant should be made to Oriental Institute. Political quarrel over Dr. Sanchez's activities in New Mexico; disposition of Spelman estate - bequest to General Education Board; administration of bequests and gifts; changes in officers and personnel. Legal status of General Education Board; crank and crackpot letters; tributes, memorials; dissolution. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Wallace Buttrick, Starr J. Murphy, Abraham Flexner, Eben C. Sage, Frederick T. Gates, Harry Pratt Judson, Jerome D. Greene, A. L. Boulware, Bertram Cutler, Henry C. Morrison.
  - General Education Board - General, 1922-1932 (Box 16, Folder 159)
    Grants to Iowa colleges; report on Southern Education Board; studies; policy decisions; reports; activities of Board members; question of whether grant should be made to Oriental Institute. Political quarrel over Dr. Sanchez's activities in New Mexico; disposition of Spelman estate - bequest to General Education Board; administration of bequests and gifts; changes in officers and personnel. Legal status of General Education Board; crank and crackpot letters; tributes, memorials; dissolution. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Wallace Buttrick, Abraham Flexner, Wickliffe Rose, Eben C. Sage, William W. Brierley, Thomas M. Debevoise, Willard S. Richardson, Arthur W. Packard, Frederick T. Gates, Robert W. Gumbel, Raymond B. Fosdick, Trevor Arnett, Edwin Embree, A. W. Armour.
  - General Education Board - General, 1933-1947 (Box 16, Folder 160)
    Grants to Iowa colleges; report on Southern Education Board; studies; policy decisions; reports; activities of Board members; question of whether grant should be made to Oriental Institute. Political quarrel over Dr. Sanchez's activities in New Mexico; disposition of Spelman estate - bequest to General Education Board; administration of bequests and gifts; changes in officers and personnel. Legal status of General Education Board; crank and crackpot letters; tributes, memorials; dissolution. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., William W. Brierley, Thomas M. Debevoise, Arthur W. Packard, Robert W. Gumbel, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Raymond B. Fosdick, Lefferts M. Dashiell, Trevor Arnett, A. W. Armour, E V. Hollis, Edgar B. Young, Jackson Davis, William I. Myers.
  - General Education Board - General, 1948-1952 (Box 17, Folder 161)
    Grants to Iowa colleges; report on Southern Education Board; studies; policy decisions; reports; activities of Board members; question of whether grant should be made to Oriental Institute. Political quarrel over Dr. Sanchez's activities in New Mexico; disposition of Spelman estate - bequest to General Education Board; administration of bequests and gifts; changes in officers and personnel. Legal status of General Education Board; crank and crackpot letters; tributes, memorials; dissolution. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., William W. Brierley, Thomas M. Debevoise, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Raymond B. Fosdick, Chauncey Belknap, Dana S. Creel, Chester Barnard, General George C. Marshall, Herbert F. Clark, Robert D. Calkins.
  - General Education Board - General, 1953-1959 (Box 17, Folder 162)
    Grants to Iowa colleges; report on Southern Education Board; studies; policy decisions; reports; activities of Board members; question of whether grant should be made to Oriental Institute. Political quarrel over Dr. Sanchez's activities in New Mexico; disposition of Spelman estate - bequest to General Education Board; administration of bequests and gifts; changes in officers and personnel. Legal status of General Education Board; crank and crackpot letters; tributes, memorials; dissolution. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Robert W. Gumbel, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Dana S. Creel, J. R. McCain, Lindsley F. Kimball, Harvie Branscomb, Dean Rusk, Chauncey Belknap, Edward Robinson.
  - General Education Board - Temporary Association, 1901-1902 (Box 17, Folder 163)
    Association before actual formation of General Education Board.
  - General Education Board - National Education Association Resolution, 1914 (Box 17, Folder 164)
    Association "viewed with alarm" the Carnegie and Rockefeller Foundations.
  - General Education Board - Gary Schools, 1915-1918 (Box 17, Folder 165)
    Study of Gary Schools; publication of studies.
  - General Education Board - December 1927 Salary Increase, 1927-1928 (Box 17, Folder 166)
    Officers' salaries raised; standards set for establishing officers' salaries.
  - General Education Board - Correspondence Regarding Candidates for Vacancies, 1935-1936 (Box 17, Folder 167)
  - General Education Board - University of Chicago - Payment to Provident Hospital, 1936 (Box 17, Folder 168)
  - General Education Board - Raymond B. Fosdick Report on General Education Board, 1944 (Box 17, Folder 169)
    Report on "The Future of the General Education Board."
  - General Education Board - Pensions, 1917-1950 (Box 17, Folder 170)
  - General Education Board - Taxation, 1910-1952 (Box 17, Folder 171)
    Exemption from taxation; tax policy; question of keeping securities in Washington.
  - General Education Board - 1952 Opinion about John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s Removal of Restrictions, 1952-1953 (Box 17, Folder 172)
    Question of whether there was any impediment to Board spending the principal of 1905 and 1907 gifts.
  - General Education Board - History of General Education Board, 1950-1954 (Box 17, Folder 173)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s talk with historian hired by General Education Board.
  - General Education Board - Dr. George Foster Peabody Correspondence, 1906-1912 (Box 17, Folder 174)
    Controversy between Frederick T. Gates and George Foster Peabody over purposes of General Education Board.
  - General Education Board - Ambassador Walter Hines Page Correspondence, 1916-1919 (Box 17, Folder 175)
    Memorial portrait of Walter Hines Page to hang in American Embassy in London. Dr. Buttrick's visit to England; invitation for John D. Rockefeller, Jr. visit to England to build morale; death of Mr. Page.
  - General Education Board - Dr. Wallace Buttrick Correspondence, 1920-1931 (Box 17, Folder 176)
    Dr. Wallace Buttrick's illness; 70th birthday gift from John D. Rockefeller, Jr.; 50th wedding anniversary. Death, 1926. Memorial. Resignation of Ernest Buttrick, auditor.
  - General Education Board - Dr. Wickliffe Rose Correspondence, 1927-1932 (Box 18, Folder 177)
    Retirement of Dr. Wickliffe Rose; establishment of trust fund for him; his death.
  - General Education Board - Dr. Eben C. Sage - Student Welfare Society, 1922-1933 (Box 18, Folder 178)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. paid salaries and expenses for work carried out through the years by Dr. Sage and others. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, Raymond B. Fosdick, T. Bartlett Sage, Eben C. Sage, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - General Education Board - Lincoln School, 1916-1922 (Box 18, Folder 179)
    Statute for administration of school; agreement between General Education Board and Teachers College of Columbia University. Question of religious instruction; construction of building; purchase of property. Success of school; deed of trust to Teachers College. Correspondents include Starr J. Murphy, Charles O. Heydt, W. A. White & Sons, Wallace Buttrick, Abraham Flexner, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., A. L. Boulware.
  - General Education Board - Lincoln School - 5th Avenue and 102nd Street Property, 1921-1924 (Box 18, Folder 180)
    Sale of property to friend of John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur Brisbane.
  - General Education Board - Finance Committee - Correspondence, 1911-1960 (Box 18, Folder 181)
    Handling of pledges; fiscal policy; purchase and sale of securities. Administration of various funds; execution of proxies; investment summaries. Correspondents include Bertram Cutler, Barton Turnbull, John D. Rockefeller, Thomas M. Debevoise, W. Brierley, Charles O. Heydt, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Trevor Arnett.
    32.5
  - General Education Board - Finance Committee - Statements, 1937-1960 (Box 18, Folder 182)
    Quarterly reports to Finance Committee, 1937-1944; statement of income and principal accounts, 1947.
  - General Education Board - Letters of Gift from John D. Rockefeller, 1902-1921 (Box 18, Folder 183)
    32.8
  - General Education Board - John D. Rockefeller - March 1, 1902 Pledge, 1901-1910 (Box 18, Folder 184)
    Pledge for $1,000,000.
  - General Education Board - John D. Rockefeller - June 30, 1905 Pledge, 1904-1909 (Box 18, Folder 185)
    Pledge for $10,000,000. Removal of original restrictions in 1909. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Frederick T. Gates, Starr J. Murphy, L. C. Myers, George Foster Peabody.
  - General Education Board - John D. Rockefeller - February 5, 1907 Pledge, 1907-1925 (Box 18, Folder 186)
    Pledge for $32,000,000. Income from gift; removal of restrictions, 1920. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Frederick T. Gates, Starr J. Murphy, Wallace Buttrick.
  - General Education Board - Bound Acknowledgment Volume Presented to John D. Rockefeller, 1907 (Box 18, Folder 187)
    Presentation volume in honor of John D. Rockefeller's gift of $32,000,000.
    32.8B
  - General Education Board - John D. Rockefeller - Pledges to University of Chicago through General Education Board, 1907-1942 (Box 19, Folder 188)
    Appropriated from 1907 gift. Correspondents include Frederick T. Gates, John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, Bertram Cutler, Harry Pratt Judson, Charles O. Heydt, Wallace Buttrick, L. C. Myers.
    32.8B1
  - General Education Board - John D. Rockefeller - Gifts to Rockefeller Institute through General Education Board, 1912-1916 (Box 19, Folder 189)
    Appropriated from 1907 gift. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, Frederick T. Gates.
    32.8B2
  - General Education Board - John D. Rockefeller - Pledge of June 9, 1909 (Box 19, Folder 190)
    Pledge for $10,000,000; lists of securities; newspaper clippings.
    32.8C
  - General Education Board - Gifts for Medical Education, 1919-1920 (Box 19, Folder 191)
    Gift of September 20, 1919 from John D. Rockefeller to General Education Board to be used for medical research. Correspondents include Abraham Flexner, Starr J. Murphy, John D. Rockefeller, W. Brierley, Lefferts M. Dashiell, Eben C. Sage.
    32.8D
  - General Education Board - Gifts for Medical Education, 1920-1921 (Box 19, Folder 192)
    Gift of December 15, 1920 from John D. Rockefeller to General Education Board to be used for medical research. Correspondents include Abraham Flexner, Starr J. Murphy, John D. Rockefeller, W. Brierley, Lefferts M. Dashiell, Eben C. Sage.
  - General Education Board - Gifts for Medical Education, 1921 (Box 19, Folder 193)
    Gift of April 5, 1921, from John D. Rockefeller to General Education Board to be used for medical research. Correspondents include Abraham Flexner, Starr J. Murphy, John D. Rockefeller, W. Brierley, Lefferts M. Dashiell, Eben C. Sage.
  - General Education Board - Gifts for Medical Education, 1925-1932 (Box 19, Folder 194)
    Gifts from John D. Rockefeller to General Education Board to be used for medical research. Correspondents include Abraham Flexner, Starr J. Murphy, John D. Rockefeller, W. Brierley, Lefferts M. Dashiell, Eben C. Sage.
  - General Education Board - December 18, 1919 Gift for Teachers' Salaries, 1919-1930 (Box 19, Folder 195)
    Gift from John D. Rockefeller to General Education Board to be used in cooperation with colleges to increase staff salaries. Correspondents include Robert W. Gumbel, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Trevor Arnett, George E. Vincent.
    32.8E
  - General Education Board - Gifts from John D. Rockefeller - Allotment Problems, 1936-1937 (Box 19, Folder 196)
    Overpayment by General Education Board to University of Chicago and consequent underpayment to Rockefeller Institute; possible indebtedness of General Education Board to Institute. Correspondents include Starr J. Murphy, Thomas M. Debevoise, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - General Education Board - Subscriptions to Colleges and Schools, 1911-1932 (Box 19, Folder 197)
    Summaries of payments and letters of thanks for General Education Board subscriptions for endowment and buildings. Correspondents include Abraham Flexner, W. Brierley, Wallace Buttrick.
    32.11
  - General Education Board - Frederick T. Gates Addresses and Reports, 1905-1911 (Box 19, Folder 198)
    "The Colleges and Rural Life," "The Purpose of the Rockefeller Foundation with Suggestions as to the Policy of Administration," "Explanation of John D. Rockefeller, Sr.'s Gift of $10,000,000." Memoranda on educational conditions and prospects in Minnesota and Nebraska.
    32.14
- International Education Board
  - International Education Board - General, 1922-1933 (Box 19, Folder 199)
    Founding of Board; Virginia charter; meetings and elections; changes in by-laws. Policy; administrative and legal details; financial correspondence. John D. Rockefeller and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. pledges and gifts. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Thomas M. Debevoise, Bertram Cutler, Arthur Woods, Willard S. Richardson, Raymond B. Fosdick, Phillip Keebler, A. L. Boulware, Charles O. Heydt, Wickliffe Rose.
    250
  - International Education Board - General, 1934-1951 (Box 19, Folder 200)
- International Health Commission
  - International Health Commission of the Rockefeller Foundation, 1915-1926 (Box 19, Folder 201)
    Successor to Rockefeller Sanitary Commission, supported directly by the Foundation. Administrative and legal details; commendations of Commission's work. Correspondents include Wickliffe Rose, John A. Ferrell, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, Willard S. Richardson, Raymond B. Fosdick, Thomas M. Debevoise, Charles O. Heydt, A. L. Boulware, George E. Vincent.
    34
- Rockefeller Brothers Fund
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - General
    Organization of fund; initial appeals. Procedures; possible projects; report on studies; changes in finances. Policy changes. Sam Rayburn Library; West African program. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Winthrop Rockefeller, David Rockefeller, Dana S. Creel.
    88
    - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - General, 1946-1952 (Box 20, Folder 202)
    - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - General, 1954 (Box 20, Folder 203)
    - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - General, 1955 (Box 20, Folder 204)
    - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - General, January-June 1956 (Box 20, Folder 205)
    - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - General, July-December 1956 (Box 20, Folder 206)
    - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - General, 1957 (Box 20, Folder 207)
    - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - General, 1958 (Box 20, Folder 208)
    - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - General, 1959 (Box 20, Folder 209)
    - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - General, 1959 (Box 20, Folder 0209A)
    - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - General, 1960 (Box 21, Folder 210)
    - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - General, 1960 (Box 21, Folder 0210A)
    - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - General, January-June 1961 (Box 21, Folder 211)
    - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - General, January-June 1961 (Box 21, Folder 0211A)
    - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - General, July-December 1961 (Box 21, Folder 212)
    - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - General, July-December 1961 (Box 21, Folder 0212A)
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - New York Academy of Osteopathy, Inc., 1957-1960 (Box 21, Folder 213)
    Study of osteopathic profession for possible support. Correspondents include Arthur Jones, W. K. Riland, Dana S. Creel, D. F. Freeman.
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - Rockefeller Center Note, 1952-1960 (Box 21, Folder 214)
    Renegotiations on Center's note given to Fund by John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - Statements, 1956 (Box 21, Folder 215)
    Statement of Operating Principles and Policies.
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - Reports, 1950-1957 (Box 21, Folder 216)
    Copies of printed annual reports.
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - Appropriations, 1941-1950 (Box 21, Folder 217)
    Details of gifts by Fund; development of policies of giving.
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - Letters Regarding Report, 1958-1959 (Box 21, Folder 218)
    Comments on "Mid-Century Challenges to U. S. Foreign Policy" both laudatory and critical. Correspondents include Nelson A. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Laurance S. Rockefeller.
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - "Prospect for America", 1961 (Box 22, Folder 219)
    Journalists' acknowledgement of receipt of book including six panel reports; words of encouragement. Correspondents include Shirley Clurman, E. J. Hughes.
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - Ramon Magsaysay Award Foundation, 1957-1958 (Box 22, Folder 220)
    Genesis of idea with Nelson A. Rockefeller and John D. Rockefeller 3rd; discussion of possible types of awards. Arrangement for handling of funds and granting of awards to commemorate and perpetuate ideals of Magsaysay. Trips to Manila by members of family. Foundation became independent Philippine agency. Correspondents include Nelson A. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Dana S. Creel, Donald McLean.
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - Ramon Magsaysay Award Foundation - 1958 Award Ceremonies, January-August 1958 (Box 22, Folder 221)
    Attended by John D. Rockefeller 3rd.